hey guys Pythagorean theorem is true for
all of these cases there's already a ton
of proofs for this version I'm not going
to worry about that in this video but I
do want to show how this version leads
to the other versions so let's do this
one how do we get from here to here
since this is an equation we can
multiply both sides by the same thing in
this case 1/2 and this 1/2 will
distribute to both of these terms and
this 1/2 will distribute here and we end
up with a^2 over 2 + b^2 2 = c^2 / 2 and
basically that's cutting all of these in
half so it ends up looking like this and
that's how to do the first one and you
can do something similar for equilateral
triangles the area of an equilateral
triangle is the < TK 3 over 4 * the base
squared so this formula would be < tk34
a 2 +34 b^2 = > 34 c^2 and you can
imagine how we get from here to there we
multiply both sides of the equation by <
tk3 over 4 this will distribute to both
of these and this distributes here and
we now have the equation we wanted it's
the same thing for regular pentagons you
just multiply both sides by a constant
the next interesting one is semicircles
the area of a semicircle is equal to PK
R 2 / 2 or you can rewrite that as < / 2
r^ 2 so this would end up being < / 2 r^
2 + < / 2 r^2 = < 2 R 2 so R sub1 is the
radius of this one that's going to be
half of the distance a so we can change
this to a over2 and then R sub 2 would
be the radius of this semicircle so
that's going to be half of B so this
will be B over2 and then the radius of
this one is going to be half of this
side length C so we'll change that to
c/2 so this is the formula for
semicircles and we can prove that this
is true we start with A2 plus b^2 = c^2
and then we'll divide both sides of the
equation by four and then on the left
side this four can be split to the two
terms we can rewrite each of these fours
as 2^ 2ar now looking at this a^ 2 over
2^ 2 we can rewrite this as a over 2 the
whole thing squared and the same thing
as b^2 over 2^2 that can be Rewritten as
B over 2^ 2 and we can do the same thing
to this it'd be C over 2^ 2 and then for
the next step we can multiply both sides
of the equation by Pi / 2 this Pi over2
will distribute to both of these terms
and on this side it will distribute here
and now we have the equation of the
semicircle Pythagorean theorem so we
went from the Pythagorean theorem that
we know to this new fun version and this
will work for any similar figures you
end up multiplying both sides of the
Pythagorean theorem by some constant how
exciting